<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">

<book>
  <title> Mobile docBook Help </title>
  <bookinfo>
    <legalnotice>
      <para>Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this
        software and associated documentation files (the <quote>Software</quote>), to deal in the
        Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify,
        merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit
        persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all
              copies or substantial portions of the Software.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Except as contained in this notice, the names of individuals credited with
              contribution to this software shall not be used in advertising or otherwise to promote
              the sale, use or other dealings in this Software without prior written authorization
              from the individuals in question.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Any stylesheet derived from this Software that is publicly distributed will be
              identified with a different name and the version strings in any derived Software will
              be changed so that no possibility of confusion between the derived package and this
              Software will exist.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <formalpara>
        <title>Warranty:</title>
        <para>THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED,
        INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
        PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL DAVID CRAMER, KASUN GAJASINGHE, OR ANY
        OTHER CONTRIBUTOR BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN
        ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE
        SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.</para>
      </formalpara>
      <para>This package is maintained by Gihan Karunarathne, <email>gckarunarathne AT gmail DOT com</email>
      and Jirka Kosek, <email>jirka AT kosek DOT cz</email>.
      </para>
      <para>This package also includes the following software written and copyrighted by others:
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Files in <filename class="directory">template/common/jquery</filename> are
              copyrighted by <ulink url="http://jquery.com/">JQuery</ulink> under the MIT License.
              The file <filename>jquery.cookie.js</filename> Copyright (c) 2006 Klaus Hartl under
              the MIT license.
            </para>
            <indexterm>
              <primary>jquery</primary>
            </indexterm>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Some files in the <filename class="directory">template/content/search</filename>
              and <filename class="directory">indexer</filename> directories were originally part of
              N. Quaine's htmlsearch DITA plugin. The htmlsearch DITA plugin is available from the
              <ulink url="http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/dita-users/files/Demos/">files
              page</ulink> of the DITA-users yahoogroup. The htmlsearch plugin was released under
              a BSD-style license. See <filename>indexer/license.txt</filename> for details.
              <indexterm>
                <primary>htmlsearch</primary>
              </indexterm>
              <indexterm>
                <primary>DITA</primary>
                <secondary>htmlsearch plugin</secondary>
              </indexterm>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Stemmers from the <ulink
              url="http://snowball.tartarus.org/texts/stemmersoverview.html">Snowball
              project</ulink> released under a BSD license.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Code from the <ulink url="http://lucene.apache.org/">Apache Lucene</ulink> search
              engine provides support for tokenizing Chinese, Japanese, and Korean content released
              under the Apache 2.0 license.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Code that provides weighted search results and some
              other improvements was graciously donated by <ulink
              url="http://www.oxygenxml.com">SyncRO Soft
              Ltd.</ulink>, the publishers of the oXygen XML
              Editor.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Cosmetic improvements provided by <ulink
              url="http://docs.openstack.org"
              >OpenStack</ulink>.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist> Mobile for DocBook was first developed as a <ulink
          url="http://code.google.com/soc/">Google Summer of Code</ulink> project.
      </para>
    </legalnotice>
    <copyright>
      <year>2012</year>
      <holder>Gihan Karunarathne</holder>
      <holder>Jirka Kosek</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Jirka</firstname>
      <surname>Kosek</surname>
      <email>jirka AT kosek DOT cz</email>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>Gihan</firstname>
      <surname>Karunarathne</surname>
      <email>gckarunarathne AT gmail DOT com</email>
    </author>
    <pubdate>August 2012</pubdate>
  </bookinfo>
  <preface>
    <title>Foreword</title>
      This is a project which is developing under GSoC-2012 and it is targeting on
      deploy DocBook content over mobile interfaces.
  </preface>

  <chapter>
    <chapterinfo>
      <abstract>
        <!-- This becomes the brief description that appears in search results UNLESS there's a para or phrase with role="summary". If there is, then the role="summary" text wins. -->
        <para>Overview of the package.</para>
      </abstract>
    </chapterinfo>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>A common requirement for technical publications groups is to produce a Web-based help
      format that includes a table of contents pane, a search feature, and an index similar to what
      you get from the Microsoft HTML Help (.chm) format or Eclipse help. If the content is help for
      a Web application that is not exposed to the Internet or requires that the user be logged in,
      then it is impossible to use services like Google to add search.
      <indexterm class="singular">
        <primary>features</primary>
      </indexterm>
      <itemizedlist>
        <title>Features</title>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sophisticated CSS-based page layout</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Client-side search.<indexterm class="singular">
            <primary>search</primary>
            <secondary>features</secondary>
          </indexterm>
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Provides full content search of the documentation. Shows the search results with
              links to chunked pages, and a small description.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <!--<listitem>
            <para>Search results scoring/rating - The results are weighted according to how many
              times the words in search query appears in it, is it bold or not, is in index terms
              etc. The score out of 5 is shown by small colored boxes after each
              search-result.
            </para>
          </listitem>-->
          <listitem>
            <para>Search results can include brief descriptions of the target.
              <indexterm class="singular">
                <primary>search</primary>
                <secondary>description</secondary>
              </indexterm>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Stemming support for English, French, and German. Stemming support can be added
              for other languages by implementing a stemmer.
                <indexterm class="singular">
                  <primary>search</primary>
                  <secondary>stemming</secondary>
                </indexterm>
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Support for Chinese, Japanese, and Korean languages using code from the Lucene search engine.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Search highlighting shows where the searched term appears in the results.
                <indexterm class="singular">
                  <primary>search</primary>
                  <secondary>highlighting</secondary>
                </indexterm>
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Table of contents (TOC) pane with collapsible toc tree.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Auto-synchronization of content pane and TOC.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Nicely placed small forward, backward, top links</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>TOC and search pane implemented without the use of a frameset.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>An Ant script to generate output. You can use this
            build file by importing it into your own or use it as a
            model for integrating this output format into your own
            build system. Alternatively, you can use this Ant script
            as a template for creating your own build script or you
            can use the
              <ulink url="http://docbkx-tools.sourceforge.net/docbkx-samples/manual.html">
                Docbkx Maven plugin
              </ulink>.
            </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </chapter>

</book>
